A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Council on Indians, 1988-2012
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Council on Indians, 1988-2012
The Library of Virginia
50420
20 cu. ft. (20 boxes)
Virginia Council on Indians
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years (Code of Virginia 42.1-78). Restricted records in this collection have been sealed or flagged but not removed from the collection. Types of sealed or flagged information may include, but are not limited to: proprietary information (2.2-3705.6) and personal information (2.2-3705.1).
Acquisition Information
Accession 50420 was transferred by Deanna Beacham, 1111 E. Broad St., Richmond, Va., 30 May 2012.
Historical Information
In 1982, House Joint Resolution 97 created the Joint Subcommittee Studying the Relationship Between the State and Indian Tribes. Out of the work of this subcommittee came the Commission on Indians, which was created by HB 455 in 1983 and started operation on 1 July 1983. The Commission was created under the Secretary of Health and Human Services and its original purpose was "to gather information, make studies, and conduct research into the Indians tribes of the Commonwealth....[and] to suggest ways to assist Virginia's Indian population in reaching its full economic and social potential." In 1985 the General Assembly changed the name to the Virginia Council on Indians.
The Council reported its findings and recommendations to the Governor and General Assembly 60 days prior to the convening of the session of the General Assembly held in each even numbered year. When it was disbanded, the Council comprised of 16 members appointed by the Governor in the following categories: Representatives from each of the eleven state tribes officially recognized by Virginia; two members at-large from the Indian population residing in Virginia; one citizen member at-large; one member from the House of Delegates appointed by the Speaker of the House; and one member from the Senate of Virginia appointed by the Senate Committee on Privileges and Elections.
In 2002, the Council was charged with creating criteria for the recognition of additional tribes and with making recommendations to the Governor on which tribes to recognize. The Council was moved under the Secretary of Natural Resources in 2004. In 2011, Governor Robert McDonnell's Commission on Government Reform and Restructuring recommended the elimination of the Virginia Council on Indians. Legislation passed by the General Assembly in 2012 abolished the Council as of 30 June 2012.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the administrative records of the Virginia Council on Indians as well as planning documents submitted to the Council. Administrative records include information related to the tribal recognition process at both the state and federal level, planning for the Jamestown 2007 celebration, preservation of historic sites, conferences both attended and run by members of the Council, and minutes and agendas for meetings of the Virginia Council on Indians. Planning documents include archaeological reviews of historic sites as well as subject files that include correspondence, memoranda of understanding, programmatic agreements, and other related material.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Administrative records
II. Planning documents
Contents List
- Series I. Administrative records, 1990-2012., Extent: 7 cu. ft. (7 boxes).
  Administrative records, 1990-2012, of the Virginia Council on Indians. There are subject files, 1990-2012, that contain information on the activities of the Virginia Council on Indians. Includes information related to the tribal recognition process at both the state and federal level, planning for the Jamestown 2007 celebration, preservation of historic sites, conferences both attended and run by members of the Council, and other activities of the Council. There are also minutes and agendas, 1998-2010, for meetings of the Virginia Council on Indians and other meetings attended by Council members, such as meetings with other departments within the Secretary of Natural Resources, meetings of the Recognition Committee, and meetings to prepare for events in which the Virginia Council on Indians is participating.
  Series I is divided into two subseries: Subject files and Minutes and agendas.
  Wherever possible, the original order of folders has been maintained.
  - Subject files, 1990-2012., 5 cu. ft. (5 boxes)
    Subject files, 1990-2012, contain information on the activities of the Virginia Council on Indians. Includes information related to the tribal recognition process at both the state and federal level, planning for the Jamestown 2007 celebration, preservation of historic sites, conferences both attended and run by members of the Council, and other activities of the Council.
    - Freedom of Information Act request, 2010. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Copies of documents related to tribal recognition, 2010. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Freedom of Information Act request for tribal recognition material, 2010. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Freedom of Information Act request for tribal recognition material, 2008. (Box 1, Folders 4-6)
    - Hand Site Excavation, 2010. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Walt Brown Letter, 2010 January 17. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cheroenhaka (Nottoway) and the Nottoway of Virginia Tribes, 2008. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cheroenhaka (Nottoway) Tribe, 2003-2010. (Box 1, Folders 10-14)
    - Cheroenhaka (Nottoway) Correspondence, 2002-2010. (Box 1, Folders 15-17)
    - Federal Recognition, 2000-2004. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Federal Recognition Letters, 2003-2004. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Federal Recognition: Resolution 754, 1998-1999. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Federal Recognition Constituent Letters, 2004. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Camilla Townsend, 2004. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Camilla Townsend, 2003. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2008-2009. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2007. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists legislation, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Stop Relic Hunting, undated. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2005. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists legislative affairs, 2006. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2003-2004. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Council of Virginia Archaeologists, 2006-2007. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Interstate Indian Council, 2004-2010. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2011. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2010. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2009. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2008. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Threatened Sites Committee, 1990-2005. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Powhatan Statue, 2003. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Black Hawk Highway Marker Dedication, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - First Landing Signage, undated. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Defense Supply Center Richmond Signage, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Charles City Markers, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - French and Indian War Marker, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Schauffler Scholarship, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Consultations: Richmond to Hampton Roads Rail, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Consultations: Virginia Legends award for Powhatan, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Consultations: Federal Highway Administration and Virginia Department of Transportation, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Consultations: Radford Army Ammunition Plant, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Consultations: Flanary Site/Duneannon, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Working Together: Developing Partnerships with American Indians in New Jersey and Delaware, undated. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Consultations: Ripley Site, 2003. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Consultations: Loudoun County, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Consultations: Museum of Natural History, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Consultations: Stafford County, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Standards of Learning, 2007-2008. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Five Ponds Press, 2008. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Teaching American History Grant, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Summit on Chesapeake Education, undated. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Chesapeake Bay Program, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Jamestown 400/Sultana, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation Initial Consultation, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Jamestown Settlement Initial Content, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2007. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Jamestown: Two Trails at Neck of Land, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Haley Sharpe/Historic Jamestowne, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Historic Jamestowne Waysides, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Jamestown Project: Historic Jamestowne Visitor Center, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Programmatic Agreement for Jamestown Development Plan, 2003-2004. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - National Park Service Programmatic Agreement for Jamestown, 2003. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - National Park Service Programmatic Agreement for Jamestown, 2003. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - National Park Service Jamestown, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Jamestown Storyboards, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - James River State Park, 2004-2005. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Captain John Smith National Historic Trail, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Captain John Smith National Historic Water Trail, 2005. (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Captain John Smith National Historic Water Trail, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Captain John Smith National Historic Water Trail draft and letter, 2006. (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - John Smith Gateway Project, 2003-2004. (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Cooperative Agreement between National Park Service, The Maryland Historical Trust, and the Virginia Department of Historic Resources, 2004. (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - John Smith Gateway Project comments 2003. (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Captain John Smith 400 Project, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Echoes of 1608, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Echoes of 1608, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Friends of the Captain John Smith Chesapeake National Historic Water Trail, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Jamestown 400 Planning, 2004. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Jamestown 2007 Indian Advisory Committee, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Conservation Fund, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - John Smith Water Trail NOAA Buoy, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Scenic Roads Map Committee, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - John Smith Water Trail Support, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Scenic Virginia, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Statement of National Significance, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Department of Conservation and Recreation Trails, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - National Geographic Society: Chesapeake, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Mariner's Museum, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Chesapeake Bay Gateways, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Chesapeake Bay Gateways, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Captain John Smith Gateway Expenses, 2003-2004. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Captain John Smith Gateway Project, 2004. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Captain John Smith Gateway Project, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Captain John Smith Gateway Project, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Chesapeake Bay Gateways Network Networking Committee, 2005. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Jamestown: Journey of Democracy, undated. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Department of Conservation and Recreation Land Conservation Workshop, 2006. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - January 2003 Minutes, 2003. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Old Attendance Lists, 1998. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Posters, undated. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - King William Reservoir: Mattaponi, 1998-1999. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Walter Plecker and the Racial Integrity Law, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - King William Reservoir: Memorandum of Agreement, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - King William Reservoir, 1998-1999. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - King William Reservoir Project Correspondence, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2003. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1996-1997. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1997-1998. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1998. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1998. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1998-1999. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - The 14th International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1997-1998. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - The 14th International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1997-1998. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - The 14th International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1998. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Tidewater Native American Support Group, undated. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Letters Sent on Behalf of the Council on Indians, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Governor's Conference on American Indian Affairs, 1999. (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - King William Reservoir, 2002. (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Michael Two Horses Memorial, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, 1997-1998. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - House Joint Resolution 159, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Burial Site, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mt. Graham Coalition, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 4H Materials, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Lewis and Clark Exposition, 2002-2003. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Birding and Wildlife Trail, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Foundations for the Humanities Funding Opportunities, 2003-2004. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Forum, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Forum, 2008. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Standards of Learning, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Council for the Social Studies, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Indians 101, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Indian Summit on Higher Education, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Indian Summit on Higher Education, 2001-2004. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Bear Saponi Tribe of Clinch Mountain Southwest Virginia, 2008-2009. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Gingaskin Nation, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Blue Ridge Cherokee, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Tauxenent Indian Nation of Virginia, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - United Cherokee Indian Tribe of Virginia, 2006-2010. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Appalachian Intertribal Heritage Association, 2006-2007. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Ani/Stohini-Unami Nation, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Nottoway of Virginia, 2006-2009. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2003. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Old Addresses, 1998. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources Meetings, 2005-2006. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - 17th Century Forum, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Department of the Interior, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Administration Policies, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Virginia Tech Online, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Data Sharing System Manual, undated. (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Virginia Time Travelers, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Sappony Freedom of Information Act Request, undated. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Rappahannock and the Tribal Recognition Criteria, 1999-2006. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Virginia Council on Indians History, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Teacher Lists, 2008. (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - State Fair, 2008. (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Trail, 2005-2006. (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Trail, 2005-2006. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Trail Amendment, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities, undated. (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Program, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Trail Draft Booklet, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Virginia Indian Heritage Program, 2007. (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Department of Education Website, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Frontier Culture Museum Lecture Series, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Public Archaeology, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - First People Revision, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Princess Pocahontas Foundation, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Osher Lifelong Learning Institute at the University of Richmond, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - The New World, undated. (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Legislation, 2003-2004. (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Appointments, 2003. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Board Profile, 2005. (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Appointments, 2004. (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Appointments, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Appointments and Tribal Designees, 2007-2006. (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Appointments, 2009. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Financial Disclosure Forms, 2005-2006. (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Virginia Council on Indians History, 2010. (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Full time position established, 2004-2005. (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Travel Regulations, 2009. (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Budget, 2007-2012. (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Virginia Indians and Education, 2009-2010. (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Mariner's Museum, 2006. (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Discovering the First Virginians, undated. (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Budget, 2005-2007. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Foundation for the Humanities Grant, 2003-2003. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Tax Tribute Information, 2003. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Small Business Administration, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Historical Society Teacher Institute, 2008. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Beyond Jamestown Teachers Institute, 2008. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Code and Bylaws, 2008. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Financial Disclosure Forms, 2009. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Freedom of Information Act, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Middle Peninsula State Park, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Middle Peninsula State Park, 2009. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2009. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2007-2008. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Indian Nations Summit on Higher Education, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - House Bill 2078, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - House Bill 1712, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Legislation, 2005. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Conference on American Indian Affairs, 2002. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Jay Hansford C. Vest, 2004. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2008. (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 2010. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2010. (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Tribal Leadership Summit, 2004. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Legislation, 2004. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Executive Report, 2003. (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Tribal recognition and Native American license plate material, 2004-2006. (Box 20)
      Tribal recognition material restricted 100 years, license plate material restricted 75 years.
  - Minutes and agendas, 1998-2010., 2 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
    Minutes and agendas, 1998-2010, for meetings of the Virginia Council on Indians. There are also minutes, agendas, and notes from other meetings attended by Council members, such as meetings with other departments within the Secretary of Natural Resources, meetings of the Recognition Committee, and meetings to prepare for events in which the Virginia Council on Indians is participating.
    - 2010 August 24. (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - 2010 July 20. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - 2010 June 15. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - 2010 May 17. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 2010 January 19. (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 2009 November 17. (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - 2009 October 20. (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - 2009 September 15. (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - 2009 May 19. (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - 2009 April 21. (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Recognition Committee Report, 2009 April 21. (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - 2009 March 17. (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - 2009 January 27. (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - 2010 Census, 2009. (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Tree Hill Farm, 2008 December. (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - 2008 October 28. (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - 2008 September 16. (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - 2008 September 16. (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - 2008 August 19. (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - 2008 August 19. (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - 2008 June 17. (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - 2008 May 20. (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - 2008 April 15. (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - 2008 March 18. (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - 2008 February 19. (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - 2008 January 15. (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Executive Report, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - 2007 November 27. (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - 2007 October 16. (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - 2007 September 18. (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Tribal Recognition Criteria, undated. (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - 2007 June 19. (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Secretary of Natural Resources Meeting, 2007 May 25. (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Queen's Visit, 2007 May 3. (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Annual Conference, 2007 May 7. (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - 2007 April 17. (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - 2007 April 17. (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Conference, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - 2007 February 20. (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - HB 2876 and SB 1136, 2007. (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - 2007 January 16. (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Agency Head Meeting, 2007 March 23. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 2006. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Executive Summary, 2006. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - 2006 November 21. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 2006 October 17. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 2006 September 19. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - 2006 August 15. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 2006 June 20. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 2006 May 16. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - 2006 April 18. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Conference, 2006. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Conference, 2006. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - 2006 February 21. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 2006 January 17. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 2005 November 15. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - 2005 October 18. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - 2005 September 20. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - 2005 July 12. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 2005 May 17. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 2005 April 19. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Tribal Leadership Summit, 2005. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 2005 January 18. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Executive Summary, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - 2004 December 2. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - 2004 October 21. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - 2004 August 17. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - 2004 July 20. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Tribal Leaders' Meeting, 2004 July 10. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - 2004 June 8. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - 2004 April 20. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Conference, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Virginia Council on Indians Conference, 2004. (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - 2004 March 16. (Box 6, Folder 33)